Now let's dive in a little deeper into freelancing platforms,
لننظر الآن بتعمق أكبر إلى منصات العمل الحر
and see how we can use them to source clients.
لنرى كيف يمكننا استخدامها لجلب العملاء.
Freelancing platform is a marketplace,
إن منصات العمل الحر كالأسواق،
a marketplace of clients and freelancers.
وهي أسواق من العملاء وموظفو العمل الحر.
Now a marketplace is all about matchmaking.
والتوفيق هو كل شيء في أي سوق.
Lots of service providers who are freelancers
حيث يرغب الكثير من موظفي العمل الحر
like you are willing to provide their services,
مثلك في تقديم خدماتهم
and lots of clients who are willing to hire these freelancers to avail their services.
ويرغب الكثير من العملاء في توظيف أولئك الموظفين للاستفادة من خدماتهم.
Now, each client in this marketplace has a task or
كل من أولئك العملاء في هذا السوق لديه عمل أو
a project that they publish on this freelancing platform in this marketplace,
مشروع ينشره على تلك منصة العمل الحر في السوق
for which they are looking for someone to work on.
ويبحث له عن شخص ليعمل عليه.
Their interest is in picking one freelancer who is
ويكون العميل مهتمًا باختيار شخصًا
available and qualified to work on that task.
متاحًا ولديه الكفاءات المطلوبة لإنجاز ذلك العمل.
Now let's walk through a mock-up of how a typical freelancing platform looks like.
لنستعرض الآن نموذجًا لما يبدو عليه الشكل التقليدي لمنصة العمل الحر.
Now as one would expect,
كما هو متوقع،
the main dashboard of
تحتوي اللوحة الرئيسية على
any freelancing platform would have a list of job requests from clients,
منصة عمل حر على لائحة من طلبات العمل التي يطلبها العملاء
which means tasks or projects that the clients want to get done.
أي المهام أو المشاريع التي يريد العملاء إنجازها.
This request usually has four elements.
وتتكون تلك الطلبات عادة من أربعة عناصر.
A title or a description of the project,
عنوان أو وصف للمشروع
which gives a brief idea of what the project is about.
والذي يعطينا فكرة عامة عنه.
Usually when you click on that specific request,
وعند النقر فوق هذا الطلب المحدد،
it leads you to another page describing this project
فهو غالبًا ما يحولك إلى صفحة أخرى تصف المشروع
in more detail if the client did put those details.
بالمزيد من التفصيل إن كان العميل قد زودها بتلك التفاصيل.
Then it also has a proposed payment type.
يحتوي الطلب أيضًا على طريقة مقترحة للدفع.
Whether fixed costs or hourly.
إما كمبلغ ثابت أو كحساب بالساعة.
Then a proposed cost that the client is willing to pay.
بعد ذلك هناك تقدير مقترح للتكلفة التي يرغب العميل في أن يدفعها.
This will either be an hourly rate or an end-to-end fixed cost,
والتي يمكن أن تكون حساب بالساعة أو حساب ثابت شامل
depending on the payment type.
بناءً على طريقة الدفع.
You will see us covering the fixed costs and the hourly rates later in this course.
وسوف نتناول الأجور الثابتة والأجور بالساعة لاحقًا في هذه الدورة التدريبية.
You'll also see different skills that the project requires.
سوف ترى أيضًا المهارات المختلفة التي يتطلبها المشروع.
This could include programming languages that they want to use,
والتي من الممكن أن تشتمل على لغة البرمجة التي سوف تستخدمها،
or off-the-shelf tools they're using,
أو على أدوات غير معتادة يستخدمونها هم،
or even high level domains like web development,
أو حتى على النطاقات عالية المستوى مثل تطوير المواقع
digital marketing, android app development, and so on.
أو التسويق الرقمي، أو تطوير تطبيقات أندرويد، وما إلى ذلك.
A dashboard would usually have a filter section
غالبًا ما تحتوي اللوحة الرئيسية أيضًا على قسم التصفية
where you could filter the type of projects that you want to see.
والذي يمكنك فيه انتقاء أنواع المشاريع التي ترغب في رؤيتها.
For example, if you're interested in projects that pay by the hour,
فإذا كنت مثلًا ترغب في رؤية المشاريع التي تدفع الأجر بالساعة
you could use that filter.
فيمكنك حينها استخدام عامل التصفية هذا.
Or if you'd like to see projects requiring some specific skills,
وإن كنت ترغب في رؤية المشاريع التي تتطلب مهارات معينة
you could filter by those skills.
فيمكنك الانتقاء بناء على تلك المهارات.
Almost all of the freelancing platforms have such useful dashboards that help you
تحتوي كل منصات العمل الحر تقريبًا على لوحات رئيسية مفيدة تساعدك
see the tasks or projects that you're looking for and apply to those.
في رؤية المهام أو المشاريع التي تبحث عنها وفي التقدم إليها.
Now it is worth mentioning here that freelancing platforms have gone a step
من المهم الآن أن نذكر أن منصات العمل الحر قد تقدمت أكثر
further and try to use Deep Tech to decide which jobs to show to which will freelancer,
وأصبحت تحاول استخدام التقنيات العميقة لتحديد أي الأعمال تظهرها لأي موظف حر
depending on a lot of parameters.
بناء على معايير كثيرة.
This enables different freelancers to see
يتيح هذا الأمر لموظفي العمل الحر المختلفين رؤية
different jobs instead of everyone seeing the same list,
أعمالًا مختلفة بدلًا من رؤية الجميع لنفس لائحة الأعمال،
hence increasing relevancy and reducing competition.
وبهذا تزيد رؤية ما هو ذا صلة وتقل المنافسة.